Register of the Joseph Freeman papers
Hoover Institution Archives
Joseph Freeman papers
1904-1966
80159
Hoover Institution Archives
187 manuscript boxes, 3 card file boxes, 1 oversize box, 1 slide box, 1 album box, 40 envelopes, 2 sound discs (81.4 linear feet)
Writings, correspondence, printed matter, notes, and photographs relating to the relation between communism and art and literature, and to communism in the United States, Mexico, and the Soviet Union.
Freeman, Joseph, 1897-1965.
Access
Box 191 closed. Use copies available.
Use copies of some sound recordings in this collection are available for immediate access. To listen to other sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 1980.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Biographical Note
1897 October 9 Born, Piratin, Poltawa, Ukraine
1904 Immigrated to the United States
1919 A.B., Columbia University
1920-1921 Reporter, Chicago Tribune and New York Daily News (in Paris and London)
1921-1923 Assistant Editor, Liberator
1924 Publicity Director, American Civil Liberties Union
1925 Author, Dollar Diplomacy (with Scott Nearing)
1925-1931 Correspondent for Tass (intermittent)
1926 Co-founder and Editor, New Masses
1926-1927 Trip to Russia as New Masses Moscow correspondent
1929 Trip to Mexico as New Masses Mexico correspondent Married Ione Robinson
1930 Author, Voices of October (with Joshua Kunitz and Louis Lozowick)
1931-1933 Editor, New Masses
1931-1933 Speaking and fundraising trips in the United States for the John Reed Clubs and the Communist Party, including accompanying Boris Pilynak to Hollywood (1931) and Henri Barbusse on a tour of the Midwest (1933)
1932 Author, The Soviet Worker
1932 Divorced Ione Robinson
1934 Co-founder, Partisan Review
1936 Author, American Testament
1936-1937 Editor, New Masses
1937 Attended Mexican Writers Conference as delegate of the League of American Writers
1938 Married Charmion von Wiegand
1939 Left the Communist Party
1940-1942 Publicity Director, American Civil Liberties Union
1943 Author, Never Call Retreat
1943-1945 Researcher, Information Please (radio show), including a U.S.O. tour in the summer of 1945
1947 Author, The Long Pursuit
1948 Publicity Director, Poet's Theatre
1948-1952 Staff member, Edward L. Bernays (public relations firm)
1953-1961 Staff member, Executive Research, Inc. (public relations firm)
1965 August 8 Died, New York City
Scope and Content of Collection
Writings, correspondence, printed matter, notes, and photographs, relating to the relation between communism and art and literature, and to communism in the United States, Mexico, and the Soviet Union.
Communism and art.; Communism and literature.; Communism--Mexico.; Communism--United States.; Communism.; Journalists.; Slides (Photography).; Sound recordings.; Soviet Union--Politics and government.
- BIOGRAPHICAL FILE, 1904-1966
  Scope and Contents note
  Biographical sketches, clippings, correspondence, legal documents, printed matter, family material, and miscellany. Arranged alphabetically by form.
  - General
    - General. Notes and miscellany, undated (Box-folder 1: 1)
    - Addresses and business cards, undated (Box-folder 1: 2)
    - Appointment books and diaries
      - 1923-1937 (Box-folder 1: 3-6)
      - 1938-1964 (Box-folder 2: 1-4)
    - Biographical sketches and resumes, 1930-1965 (Box-folder 3: 1-2)
    - Clippings, 1933-1965. (Box-folder 3: 3)
      SEE ALSO: SPEECHES AND WRITINGS (PROSE) FILE/Announcements and printed matter
    - Identification cards, 1920-1962 (Box-folder 3: 4)
    - Invitations, 1934-1964 (Box-folder 3: 5)
    - Miscellaneous notebooks. For more clearly compositional notes
      SEE: SPEECHES AND WRITINGS
      - Undated (Box-folder 3: 6-7)
      - Undated (Box-folder 4: 1-4)
      - 1918-1940 (Box-folder 4: 5-7)
      - 1941-1955 (Box-folder 5: 1-6)
      - 1956-1960 (Box-folder 6: 1-5)
      - 1960-1962 (Box-folder 7: 1-5)
      - 1962-1964 (Box-folder 8: 1-7)
  - Death. Certificate and condolence letters, 1965 (Box-folder 9: 1)
  - Employment. Correspondence, 1940-1957. (Box-folder 9: 2)
    SEE ALSO: PUBLIC RELATIONS FILE
  - Family
    SEE ALSO: CORRESPONDENCE FILE
    - Freedman, Isaac. Letter and miscellany, 1904-1938 (Box-folder 9: 3)
    - Freedman, Stella. Letters and miscellany, 1940-1951 (Box-folder 9: 4)
  - Finances. Correspondence, bank statements, account books, legal and tax documents, 1930-1966 (Box-folder 9: 5-6)
  - Finances (Box-folder 10: 1-6)
  - Health. Medical records, 1939-1965 (Box-folder 10: 7)
  - Marriage. Divorce documents, letter, and marriage license, 1932-1937 (Box-folder 10: 8)
- CORRESPONDENCE, 1915-1965
  Family and personal correspondence, arranged alphabetically by correspondent.
  - General
    - General. Unidentified
      - General, 1920-1969 (Box-folder 11: 1-18)
      - Chronological, 1915-1965 (Box-folder 11: 19-22)
    - Alphabetical miscellaneous, 1918-1965 (Box-folder 12: 1-22)
  - Aaron, Daniel, 1955-1965 (Box-folder 13: 1-2)
  - Abel, Lionel, 1963 (Box-folder 13: 3)
    Includes writing by Abel, 1942
  - Abrahamsen, David, 1961 (Box-folder 13: 4)
  - Abrams, Charles, 1948-1959 (Box-folder 13: 5)
  - Abrams, Ruth, 1962 (Box-folder 13: 6)
  - Adler, Nathan, 1933-1936 (Box-folder 13: 7)
  - Adomian, Lan, 1939 (Box-folder 13: 8)
  - Aisen, Maurice and Gid Cary, 1934-1955 (Box-folder 13: 9)
  - Albee, George, 1938-1954. (Box-folder 13: 10)
    Includes writings by Albee
  - Alberto, Elise, 1933-1934 (Box-folder 13: 11)
  - Alberts, Julien, 1942-1945 (Box-folder 13: 12)
  - Aldin, Peter, 1955 (Box-folder 13: 13)
  - Allen, Devere, 1937 (Box-folder 13: 14)
  - Amberg, Ruth, 1924 (Box-folder 13: 15)
  - American Institute of Public Opinion (George Gallup), 1953 (Box-folder 13: 16)
  - American League of Ex-Servicemen, 1935 (Box-folder 13: 17)
  - Americas, 1935 (Box-folder 13: 18)
    SEE ALSO: Komorowski, Conrad
  - Amussen, Theodore S., 1947-1956 (Box-folder 13: 19)
    SEE ALSO: SPEECHES AND WRITINGS/Correspondence/Farrar & Reinhart
  - Anderson, Regina, 1925 (Box-folder 13: 20)
  - Anderson, Sherwood, 1932-1933 (Box-folder 13: 21)
  - Andrews, Martin, 1942 (Box-folder 13: 22)
  - Anshen, Ruth Nanda, 1954 (Box-folder 13: 23)
  - Anthony, John J. and Etille, 1945-1964 (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Archer, Alma, 1936 (Folder 2)
  - Arendt, Hannah, 1953-1955 (Folder 3)
    Includes writing by Arendt
  - Arens, Egmont, 1951-1955 (Folder 4)
  - Arnold, Maria and Alex Rado, 1938-1941 (Folder 5)
    Includes writings by Arnold and Rado
  - Aronoff, Jacob, 1939 (Folder 6)
  - Arvin, Newton, 1932 (Folder 7)
  - Ausubel, Bertha, 1925 (Folder 8)
  - Authors Club, 1940-1946 (Folder 9)
  - Bach, Federico, 1931-1958 (Folder 10)
  - Badash, Joseph, 1935 (Folder 11)
  - Bakshy, Alexander, 1932-1934 (Folder 12)
  - Balbalian, Joe, 1951-1956 (Folder 13)
  - Baldwin, Roger, 1924-1964 (Folder 14-15)
    Includes speech by Baldwin
  - Balkin, Harry H., 1938 (Folder 16)
  - Ballou, Jenny, 1943-1946 (Folder 17)
  - Barbusse, Henri, 1933-1934 (Folder 18)
  - Barjansky, Katya, 1941 (Folder 19)
  - Barnes, Keith, 1965. (Folder 20)
    Includes writing by Barnes
  - Barnes, Morris, 1935-1936 (Folder 21)
  - Barton, V. M., 1943 (Folder 22)
  - Basshe, Em Jo, 1931 (Folder 23)
  - Bavly, Ben and Bessie, 1933 (Folder 24)
  - Bayer, Max, 1943 (Folder 25)
  - Beals, Carleton, 1931-1951 (Folder 26)
  - Beard, Mary Ritter, 1948 (Folder 27)
  - Bedacht, Max, 1925 (Folder 28)
  - Bedard, Pierre, 1951 (Folder 29)
  - Behre, Edwine, 1955-1956 (Folder 30)
  - Bell, Daniel, 1951 (Folder 31)
  - Bendiner, Robert, 1940-1961 (Folder 32)
  - Benedict, Libbian, 1924-1926. (Folder 33)
    Includes writing by Benedict
  - Benet, Mrs. Stephen Vincent, 1943 (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Ben-Or, Judith, 1945 (Folder 2)
  - Benjamin Lehv, Florence, 1939 (Folder 3)
  - Benouville, Guillain de, 1947 (Folder 4)
  - Bernadete, M. J., 1940 (Folder 5)
  - Bernstien, Oscar and Rebecca [Drucker], 1931-1964 (Folder 6)
  - Beskin, Ossip, 1935 (Folder 7)
  - Bessie, Alvah, 1939 (Folder 8)
  - Best Maugard, Adolfo, undated (Folder 9)
  - Betancourt, Romulo, 1937 (Folder 10)
  - Beyer, Mary, 1940-1941 (Folder 11)
  - Billington, Ray A., 1953 (Folder 12)
  - Black, Harriet, 1935 (Folder 13)
  - Black, Helen, 1925-1940 (Folder 14)
  - Blake, Pat, 1962-1963 (Folder 15)
  - Blankfort, Mike, 1934-1947 (Folder 16)
  - Blanshard, Julia, 1931 (Folder 17)
  - Blanshard, Paul, undated (Folder 18)
  - Blay, Helen, 1939-1940 (Folder 19)
  - Blech, Bill, 1937-1938 (Folder 20)
  - Blitzstein, Marc, 1938 (Folder 21)
  - Block, Harry, 1934-1940 (Folder 22)
  - Block, Lou, undated (Folder 23)
  - Bobby, Lettice (sister of Ivy Litvinov), 1959 (Folder 24)
  - Boissevain, Eugene, 1937 (Folder 25)
  - Boorstin, Ruth, 1941 (Folder 26)
  - Borowitz, Lena, 1922-1923 (Folder 27)
  - Bourke-White, Margaret, 1931-1963 (Folder 28)
  - Bovingdon, John, 1932-1934. (Folder 29)
    Includes clipping, 1943
  - Bowen, Stirling, 1939 (Folder 30)
  - Bower, Warren, 1935-1937 (Folder 31)
  - Braca, Marjorie and Ernest, 1935 (Folder 32)
  - Brand, Jean, 1938 (Folder 33)
  - Bransten, Richard, 1934-1935 (Folder 34)
  - Brant, Neil, 1931-1934. (Folder 35)
    Includes writing by Brant
  - Breines, Simon, 1933-1934 (Folder 37)
  - Breger, Etta, 1951 (Folder 36)
  - Brenner, Anita, 1953-1958 (Folder 38)
    Includes printed matter
  - Brian, Rebecca, 1925 (Folder 39)
  - Bright, John, 1933-1944 (Folder 40)
  - Bright, Rose, undated (Folder 41)
  - Broch, Hermann, 1941-1947 (Folder 42)
  - Bromberg, J. Edward, 1936-1937 (Folder 43)
  - Browder, Earl, 1932-1961. (Box 16, Folder 1)
    Includes a report by Freeman relating to the New Masses
  - Brown, Clarice F., 1941 (Folder 2)
  - Brown, Esther, 1958 (Folder 3)
  - Brown, Natalie, 1924-1925 (Folder 4)
  - Brown, Neil, 1925 (Folder 5)
  - Browne, Jane, 1951 (Folder 6)
  - Bruch, Hilde, 1952-1957 (Folder 7)
    Includes writings by Bruch and letters to others
  - Bruwer, Andre, 1938 (Folder 8)
  - Bull, Rosemarie, 1953-1958 (Folder 9)
  - Bunin, Louis and Alice, 1929-1931 (Folder 10)
  - Burnham, Grace, 1924 (Folder 11)
  - Burr, Jane, 1947-1949 (Folder 12)
  - Calder, Alexander, 1954 (Folder 13)
  - Calderon, Jose, 1934 (Folder 14)
  - Calverton, V. F., 1923-1932 (Folder 15)
  - Cannon, James P., 1963 (Folder 16)
  - Cantwell, Robert, 1941 (Folder 17)
  - Capouya, Emile, 1961-1963 (Folder 18)
  - Carmon, Walter, 1932-1934 (Folder 19)
  - Casals, Pablo, 1955 (Folder 20)
  - Cassidy, James B., 1941-1949 (Folder 21)
  - Castle, Beatrice, 1929-1946 (Folder 22)
  - Causey, James H., 1938 (Folder 23)
  - Cerf, Bennett, 1938-1956 (Folder 24)
    Includes letter by Rockwell Kent
  - Chamberlain, John, 1939-1940 (Folder 25)
  - Chambers, Whittaker, circa 1931 (Folder 26)
  - Charak, Walter and Amy, 1939-1964 (Folder 27)
  - Chase, Stuart, 1932 (Folder 28)
  - Cheifetz, Sonia, 1921 (Folder 29)
  - Cherne, Leo, 1947-1953 (Folder 30)
  - Childs, Richard Storrs, 1940 (Folder 31)
  - Chramroff, Comrade, 1923 (Folder 32)
  - Clark, Blake, 1935 (Folder 33)
  - Clark, Joe, 1957 (Folder 34)
  - Clark, Judy, 1963 (Folder 35)
  - Cohen, Elliot E., 1946-1952 (Folder 36)
  - Cohen, Helen, 1938-1939 (Folder 37)
  - Cohen, Lester, 1934 (Folder 38)
  - Cohen, Mildred, 1935-1937 (Folder 39)
  - Cohen, Morris, 1935-1949 (Folder 40)
  - Cole, Gordon and Mal Stuart, 1935-1940 (Folder 41)
  - Conrad, Earl, 1956-1957 (Folder 42)
  - Contreras, Carlos (Vittorio Vidali), 1932 (Folder 43)
  - Copley, Al, 1962-1964 (Folder 44)
  - Corey, Lewis (Louis C. Fraina) and Esther, 1933-1963 (Folder 45)
    Includes printed article by Esther Corey
  - Coslow, Judith, 1934 (Folder 46)
  - Cousins, Norman, 1941-1963 (Folder 47)
  - Cowley, Malcolm, 1932-1957 (Folder 48)
  - Craig, Jean, 1963 (Folder 49)
  - Crichton, Kyle (Robert Forsythe), 1931-1940 (Folder 50)
  - Croll, June, 1932 (Folder 51)
  - Crone, Harry, undated (Folder 52)
  - Daily Worker, Includes correspondence with Bill Dunne, Gertrude Haessler, Helen Sheriden, Marguerite Young, Seymour Waldman and others, 1925-1936 (Folder 53)
  - Daixel, S., 1921 (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - Dana, Harry W. L., 1933-1938 (Folder 2)
    Includes writing by A. Fairfield Dana
  - Daniell, Blanche, 1947 (Folder 3)
  - Darcy, Sam, 1933-1958 (Folder 4)
  - Davies, Joseph E., 1943-1944 (Folder 5)
  - Davis, Anna N., 1925 (Folder 6)
  - Davis, Daniel L., 1943 (Folder 7)
  - Davis, H. David, 1952 (Folder 8)
  - Davis, Jerome, 1930 (Folder 9)
  - Davis [Rosenblum], Tobe, 1945-1953 (Folder 10)
    Includes correspondence with others and miscellany; SEE ALSO: SPEECHES AND WRITINGS/General/Collaborative and translation projects
  - Davison, Dr., 1950-1953 (Folder 11)
  - Dayal, Rajah, 1953 (Folder 12)
  - De Antonio, Emile, 1963 (Folder 13)
  - Decter, Moshe, 1955-1956 (Folder 14)
  - Dehn, Adolf, undated (Folder 15)
  - DeLappe, W. R., 1933-1934 (Folder 16)
  - Dell, Floyd, 1921-1964
    SEE ALSO: Newberry Library (Stanley Pargellis)
    - Undated (Folder 17)
    - 1921-1951 May (Folder 18-22)
    - 1951 June - 1952 December (Box 18, Folder 1-7)
    - 1953 February - 1964 (Box 19, Folder 1-6)
  - Dennen, Leon, undated (Folder 7)
  - Denoyer, Pierre, 1921 (Folder 8)
  - De Toledano, Ralph, 1941 (Folder 9)
  - Detzer, Dorothy, 1938-1939 (Folder 10)
  - Digest and Review, 1945 (Box 20, Folder 1)
  - Dinamov, Sergei, 1927-1938 (Folder 2-3)
    Includes writings by Dinamov and a copy of a letter to Theodore Dreiser
  - Diz, Ricardo, 1934 (Folder 4)
  - Doesburg, Nellie van, 1945-1951 (Folder 5)
  - Dorais, Bill, 1963-1965 (Folder 6)
  - Douglas, Helen, 1952-1953 (Folder 7)
  - Draper, Theodore, 1938-1964 (Folder 8-9)
    Includes writing by Draper and comments by Earl Browder on Draper's study of communism in the U.S.
  - Dreiser, Theodore, 1931 (Folder 10)
  - Drucker, Esther and Dave, 1935-1957 (Folder 11)
  - Dublin, Frances, undated (Folder 12)
  - Duc, Carlos le, 1937 (Folder 13)
  - Duchamp, Marcel, 1947 (Folder 14)
  - Duke, Ellen Hess, 1949 (Folder 15)
  - Dunlop, Charles, 1957-1959 (Folder 16)
  - Dunlop, Lane, 1964 (Folder 17)
  - Dunn, Robert, 1925-1935 (Folder 18)
  - Dunne, Edith Hart, 1934 (Folder 19)
  - Dunne, William, undated (Folder 20)
  - Dupee, Fred, 1937 (Folder 21)
  - Durant, Kenneth, 1932-1940. (Folder 22)
    SEE ALSO: SPEECHES AND WRITINGS (PROSE)/TASS dispatches, 1929 and SUBJECT FILE/TASS
  - Duranty, Walter, 1944 (Folder 23)
  - Dusanne, Zoe, 1947-1965 (Folder 24)
  - Earle, Edward M., 1919-1949 (Folder 25)
  - Eastman, Crystal, 1924 (Folder 26)
  - Eastman, Max, circa 1923-1962 (Folder 27)
  - Eddy, Harriet G., 1927-1938 (Folder 28)
  - Edelman, John, 1924-1948 (Folder 29)
  - Edman, Irwin, 1919-1954. (Box 21, Folder 1-2)
    Includes letters by Horace Friess and Lester Markel
  - Edward McDowell Association, 1957-1961 (Folder 3)
  - Eichen, Claus L., 1937 (Folder 4)
  - Eisenberg, Emanuel, 1936 (Folder 5)
  - Eisenstein, Sergei, 1927-1956. (Folder 6)
    Includes letter by another
  - Eisler, Hanns, 1938-1940. (Folder 7)
    Includes correspondence with another
  - Ellis, Ethel and Fred, 1938-1940 (Folder 8)
  - Elsmie, Dorine, 1921-1922. (Folder 9)
    Includes poems by Elsmie
  - Emmart, A. D. and Ruth, 1923-1932 (Folder 10)
  - Enamorado y Cuesta, Jose, 1938-1939 (Folder 11)
  - Enters, Agna, 1937 (Folder 12)
  - Epstein, Ida, 1941 (Folder 13)
  - Ernst, Morris, 1939-1952 (Folder 14)
  - Erskine, Dorothy, 1933-1934 (Folder 15)
  - Erskine, Florence, 1933 (Folder 16)
  - Eskenaz, Mina, 1933-1934 (Folder 17)
  - Estorick, Ely, 1934 (Folder 18)
  - Estorick, Eric, 1950-1963 (Folder 19)
  - Ettinger, Eve, 1943 (Folder 20)
  - Evans, Ernestine (Mrs. Kenneth Durant), 1928-1959. (Folder 21)
    Includes writing by Evans
  - Ewart, Elise ("Hedda"), 1926-1938 (Folder 22)
  - Ewart, Minna, 1936-1940. (Folder 23)
    Includes material relating to the incarceration of Arthur and Elise Ewart in Brazil and Germany
  - Fadiman, Clifton, 1945-1955. (Folder 24)
    Includes writings by Fadiman and others
  - Fadiman, William, 1939 (Folder 25)
  - Falkowski, Edward J., 1926-1930 (Folder 26)
  - Farrell, James T., 1949-1958. (Folder 27)
  - Fearing, Kenneth, 1935. (Box 22, Folder 1)
    Includes obituary, 1961
  - Feibleman, James K., 1947-1963 (Folder 2)
  - Feist, Ray, 1944-1945 (Folder 3)
  - Felsen, Henry and family, 1936-1939 (Folder 4)
  - Fennington, Sylvia, 1933-1935 (Folder 5)
  - Fensterwald, Elaine, 1954 (Folder 6)
  - Fernsworth, Lawrence, 1941 (Folder 7)
  - Field, Alice Withrow, 1932 (Folder 8)
  - Finkelstein, Louis, 1954 (Folder 9)
  - Fischer, George, 1939?-1958 (Folder 10)
  - Fischer, Louis, 1925-1958. (Folder 11)
    Includes writing by Fischer
  - Fisher, H. H., 1933-1935 (Folder 12)
  - Fitts, Norman, undated (Folder 13)
  - Fleisher, Alexander, 1934 (Folder 14)
  - Flexner, Agnes Halsey, 1949 (Folder 15)
  - Flores, Angel, 1938-1939 (Folder 16)
  - Flynn, Elizabeth Gurley, 1925-1937 (Folder 17)
  - Folsom, Frank and Mary Elting, 1937-1939 (Folder 18)
  - Frank, Nelson, 1935 (Folder 19)
  - Frank, Waldo, 1925-1934 (Folder 20)
  - Frank, Walter, 1951 (Folder 21)
  - Freedman [Feynman] [Lapidus], Anne, 1920-1961. (Folder 22)
    Includes correpondence with others
  - Freedman, Isaac and Stella, 1917-1950 (Folder 23)
  - Freedman, Nathaniel, 1924-1957 (Box 23, Folder 1)
  - Freedman, Marion, undated
    SEE: Smith, Marion [Freedman] and William
  - Freedman, Selma, undated
    SEE: Ramsey, David (Hyman Rosen) and Selma [Freedman]
  - Freedman [Hilton], Sonya, 1920-1956 (Folder 2)
  - Freeman, Elizabeth, undated (Folder 3)
  - Freeman, Harry, 1924-1964 (Folder 4-5)
  - Freeman, Joseph, 1943-1945 (Folder 6)
  - Frenkel, Lucy and family, 1934-1951 (Folder 7)
  - Freudenheim, Mendel, 1938-1939 (Folder 8)
  - Freytag-Loringhoven, Elsa von, 1922 (Folder 9)
  - Fried, Rose, 1965 (Folder 10)
  - Friedman, Charles, 1939 (Folder 11)
  - Friedman, George, 1934-1953 (Folder 12)
  - Friedman, Jack, 1934-1951. (Folder 13-14)
    SEE ALSO: SPEECHES AND WRITINGS (PROSE)/"Letters from Spain," 1960
  - Friedman, Samuel H. (Call), 1943 (Folder 15)
  - Fries, Margaret, 1941-1951 (Folder 16)
  - Fuchs, James, 1923-1926 (Folder 17)
  - Fuente, Julio de la, Includes correspondence with another, 1935-1937. (Box 24, Folder 1)
  - Fuller, Wes, circa 1940 (Folder 2)
  - Funaroff, Sol (Dynamo), 1934-1935 (Folder 3)
  - Gannett, Lewis, 1925-1951 (Folder 4)
  - Garcia Villa, Jose, 1943 (Folder 5)
  - Gardiner, Reginald, 1945-1946 (Folder 6)
  - Garlin, Sender, 1930-1937 (Folder 7)
  - Geer (Ghere), William, 1933-1935 (Folder 8)
  - Geffen, Hana, 1920-1922 (Folder 9)
  - Geissler, Lucy ("Greta") and Fritz, 1926-1948 (Folder 10)
  - Gelber, Lionel, 1951-1963 (Folder 11)
  - Gellhorn, Martha, undated (Folder 12)
  - Gendell, Mitzi, 1956 (Folder 13)
  - Gessner, Robert, 1932-1944 (Folder 14)
  - Gibson, Lydia (Mrs. Robert Minor), 1923-1952 (Folder 15-16)
  - Gibson, Roland, 1925-1926 (Folder 17)
  - Gilbert, Emanuel, 1957 (Folder 18)
  - Gilkes, Lillian, 1937 (Folder 19)
  - Ginzburg, Benjamin, 1919-1962. (Folder 20)
    Includes writings by Ginzburg
  - Ginzburg, Israel, 1920-1922 (Folder 21)
  - Gleason, Elsie, 1947-1955 (Folder 22)
  - Gold, Michael (Irwin Granich), 1922-1939 (Folder 23)
  - Goldberg, Sam, 1940-1941 (Box 25, Folder 1)
  - Goldman, Minnie, 1922 (Folder 2)
  - Goldstein, Esther, 1921 (Folder 3)
  - Golenpaul, Dan and Ann, 1944-1945 (Folder 4)
  - Goll, Ivan, 1940 (Folder 5)
  - Goll, Ralph, undated (Folder 6)
  - Gomez, Manny, 1925-1932 (Folder 7)
  - Gordon, Dave, 1928 (Folder 8)
  - Gottschalk, Fruma and Louis, 1922-1961 (Folder 9)
  - Gould, Joseph, 1932 (Folder 10)
  - Graham, John, 1955 (Folder 11)
  - Grant, Hazel, 1933-1934 (Folder 12)
  - Greenberg, Clement, 1944-1945 (Folder 13)
  - Greene, Helga, 1956 (Folder 14)
  - Gregory, Horace, 1935-1961 (Folder 15)
  - Griffith, Sanford, 1933-1940 (Folder 16)
  - Gross, Bert, 1937 (Folder 17)
  - Grossinger, Jenny, 1937-1938 (Folder 18)
  - Gumberg, Alexander and Frances Adams, 1931-1963 (Folder 19)
  - Gutmann, Heinrich (Enrique), 1938. (Folder 20)
  - Hacker, Louis, 1933-1952 (Folder 21)
  - Hackforth, Norman, 1945. (Folder 22)
    Includes musical composition by Hackforth
  - Hagen, Louis, 1951 (Folder 23)
  - Hagen, Paul, 1943 (Folder 24)
  - Haidar, Naomi, 1933 (Folder 25)
  - Hall, Livingston, undated (Folder 26)
  - Halperin, Mary, 1931-1933 (Folder 27)
  - Hammett, Constance, 1934-1946 (Folder 28)
  - Hapgood, Hutchins, 1934 (Folder 29)
  - Hapgood, Powers, 1925 (Folder 30)
  - Harap, Louis, 1938-1939 (Folder 31)
  - Harcourt, Brace and Company, Inc., 1939-1949 (Folder 32)
  - Hardman, J. B. S., 1924-1926 (Folder 33)
  - Hardwicke, Cedric, 1943 (Folder 34)
  - Hargrave, Roger, 1938-1939 (Folder 35)
  - Harkonen, Sulo, 1933-1934 (Folder 36)
  - Harper and Brothers, 1950-1958. (Folder 37)
    Includes correspondence with Simon Michael Bessie, Cass Canfield, and D. W. Brogan and a transcription of the comments about Freeman published by Brogan
  - Harris, Martin, 1951-1955 (Folder 38)
  - Hart, Henry and Marian, 1934-1951 (Folder 39)
  - Harvard University. Nieman Foundation for Journalism, 1939 (Folder 40)
  - Haste, Gwendolen, undated (Folder 41)
  - Hathaway, Clarence (?), 1936 (Folder 42)
  - Hayes, Alfred, 1935-1944. (Folder 43)
    Includes letters to others
  - Hays, Arthur Garfield, 1941 (Folder 44)
  - Heiman, Beatrice, 1935 (Folder 45)
  - Hellgren, Nora, 1933-1936 (Folder 46)
  - Henle, James, 1931-1935 (Folder 47)
  - Herbert, Winifred Barnes, 1920-1922 (Folder 48)
  - Herbst, Josephine, 1925-1963 (Folder 49)
  - Herz, Henriette and Philip Cohen, 1937-1938 (Folder 50)
  - Hewitt, Melanie, 1951 (Folder 51)
  - Hicks, Granville, 1932-1958. (Box 26, Folder 1)
    Includes writings by Hicks. SEE ALSO: SPEECHES AND WRITINGS/1936 June 16
  - Hindus, Maurice, 1935-1955 (Folder 2)
  - Hines, Ted, 1951 (Folder 3)
  - Hirsch, Sarah, 1943-1945 (Folder 4)
  - Hitchcock, Virginia, 1934 (Folder 5)
  - Hodes, Jerome, 1940 (Folder 6)
  - Hoffman, Frederick J., 1944-1945. (Folder 7)
    Includes writing by Hoffman
  - Hoffman, Stanford E., 1956? (Folder 8)
    Includes poems by Hoffman
  - Holmes, Eugene, 1938 (Folder 9)
  - Holtman, Alice, 1938-1939 (Folder 10)
  - Holty, Carl, 1953 (Folder 11)
  - Horn, A. C., 1943-1950 (Folder 12)
  - Hough, Fred and Alice, 1944-1947 (Folder 13)
  - Howard, Langley and Adelaide, 1934 (Folder 14)
  - Howard, Sidney, 1932-1933 (Folder 15)
  - Howe, Quincy, 1938. (Folder 16)
    Includes book review, 1941
  - Huberman, Leo, 1956 (Folder 17)
  - Huebsch, Ben W., 1925-1938 (Folder 18)
  - Hughes, Langston, 1936 (Folder 19)
  - Hunt, Bert, 1944-1949 (Folder 20)
  - Icaza, Jorge, 1935-1938 (Folder 21)
  - International Labor Defense, 1934 (Folder 22)
  - Israel, Mack, 1933-1934 (Folder 23)
  - Jacobs, Douglas, 1938 (Folder 24)
  - Jacobson, Hazel E., 1942-1949 (Folder 25)
  - Jacobson, Max, 1943-1963. (Folder 26)
    Includes writing by Jacobson
  - Jaffe, Irma, 1951-1954 (Folder 27)
  - Jaffe, Jean, 1934-1951 (Folder 28)
  - Jaffe, Philip and Aggie, 1953-1963 (Folder 29)
  - James, Daniel Lewis, 1933 (Folder 30)
  - Janeway, Eliot and Elizabeth, 1943-1956. (Folder 31)
    Includes writings by Eliot and Elizabeth Janeway
  - Jerome, V. J., 1935-1939 (Box 27, Folder 1)
  - Jessup, John K., 1948-1951 (Folder 2)